happy
Sabbath and yes I still get to say good
morning uh praise the Lord for that song
that was a song I could listen to twice
in a row and I don't know if you're
listening to the words um you know I
guess sitting up here I can't really you
know hear the words cuz they're going
that but what I heard I was like wow
those are some really nice and
prophetic words and uh that was a
beautiful song that was a beautiful song
and um yeah praise God for that praise
God for that all right
so uh are you ready to get into the word
this morning let's uh have a word of
prayer then I'd like to invite you to
turn with me to the Book of Genesis
we're going to be looking at chapter
37 Genesis chapter 37 the sermon is
entitled this morning a time of Plenty a
time of Plenty let's pray Heavenly
Father I want to ask Lord that you would
please speak to us uh for the next few
moments help us Lord to catch a glimpse
of our mission and purpose in this world
we pray it in jesus' name amen Genesis
37 beginning with verse 1 Genesis
37 and verse
one the Bible says and Jacob dwelt in
the land wherein his father was a
stranger in the land of Canaan these are
the generations of Jacob Joseph being 17
years old was feeding the flock with his
Brethren and the lad was with the sons
of bilha and the sons of Zila his
father's wife and Joseph brought unto
his father their evil report we're going
to be talking about the story of Joseph
this morning and I want you to notice
something right off the
bat uh Joseph and his brothers appear
not to get
along and what's interesting about this
story is that the Bible tells us that
that uh Joseph had a different mother
than the other brothers and so even
though they all had the same father uh
Jacob or Israel uh they had different
mothers so they were in a sense of
different uh different um uh backgrounds
uh different folds if you will uh there
were some brothers of this fold and some
brothers of that fold but Joseph
belonged to his father and a different
mother and so the Bible tells us here we
notice rather that Joseph is one of the
youngest Brothers there's only one
younger than him but he's one of the
youngest Brothers he's like you know in
in a way we would call him like the the
new kid on the Block right you got all
these brothers above you older than you
and Joseph is is one of the youngest uh
notice with me verse verse three again
or rather verse two the Bible says last
part of that verse and Joseph brought
unto his father their evil report now we
don't know what evil they were doing but
one thing we do know is that they were
doing evil and this uh uh this suggests
that Joseph was a good man amen uh this
suggests that Joseph was a true uh uh
follower of God and they hated Joseph
because he followed god um these
brothers were
were they enjoyed sin it
appears and so they weren't really into
God's Commandments but Joseph they hated
Joseph because he kept his father's
Commandments amen I mean not amen that
they hated him but amen that he kept his
father's Commandments all right amen
amen um and so the Bible says here in
verse three now Israel loved Joseph more
than all his children because he was the
son of his old age and he made him a
coat of many colors and when his brother
his Brethren saw that their father loved
him more than all his Brethren they
hated him and could not speak peaceably
unto him so they just did not like
Joseph because they felt that he was uh
the favorite of their father now uh um
it's it's as though they treated Joseph
as though he were not one of them you
are different from us you're not one of
us and then I want you to notice what
happens to make matters worse in verse 5
and Joseph dreamed a dream and he told
it his Brethren and they hated him yet
the more so check this out Joseph is
given a Dream by God
and uh we're going to see what this
dream is about in a moment but this
dream was foretelling events to come in
the future and when his brothers heard
the the dream and the interpretation
they hated him even more so let's see
what he dreamed he said unto them here I
pray you this dream which I have dreamed
for behold we were binding sheaves in
the field this is verse 7 and lo my
sheath arose and also stood upright and
behold your sheath stood around about
and made obedience to my sheath and his
Brethren said to him sh thou indeed re
over us or shall thou indeed have
dominion over us and they hated him yet
the more for his dreams and for his
words and yet and he dreamed yet another
dream and told it his Brethren and said
behold I have dreamed a dream more and
behold the Sun and the Moon and the 11
stars made obedience to me and he told
it to his father and his Brethren and
his father rebuked him and said unto him
what what is this dream that thou has
dreamed shall I and thy mother and thy
Brethren indeed come to bow down
ourselves to thee to the
Earth and his Brethren envied him but
his father observed the saying and so
you get the sense here that because uh
God is now speaking to Jacob and
revealing to him things to come uh in
the future regarding his brothers that
the brothers hate him even more yeah we
are going to bow down to you can you
imagine the animosity that they must
have had toward
Joseph notice with me verse
12 verse 12 the Bible says and his
Brethren went to feed their flock their
father's flock in
sheim and Israel said unto Joseph do not
thy Brethren feed the flock in Shem come
and I will send thee unto them and he
said to him here I am so now Jacob or
Israel says to to Joseph Joseph I want
you to go check on your brothers on
their welfare and how do you think the
brothers felt about
that you know if they know what their
father was doing they would you know
they would have had anger and we don't
have to assume or guess because we're
going to see what happens in the story
verse uh verse 14 he said to him go I
pray thee see whether it be well with
thy Brethren and well with the flocks
and bring me word again so he sent him
out of the veil of heon and he came to
sh K now I got a question for you what
did did did did Israel or Jacob same
name same person what did Jacob send
Joseph to
do to go check on his brothers who were
given the task of
what
feeding the flock so he says go see if
it's well with them and so Jacob goes
and what do you think Jacob is going to
find if he found an evil report 4 what
do you think he was going to
find I'm sorry Joseph what do you think
Joseph was going to find he's probably
going to find something not good right
well what happens Joseph finds his
brothers and uh if you take a look at
verse um verse
17 or rather Verse 18 and when they saw
him AAR off even before he came near
unto them they conspired against him to
slay him and they said one to another
behold this dreamer cometh come now
there therefore and let us slay him and
cast him into some pit and we will say
some evil Beast has devoured him and we
shall see what shall become of his what
dreams okay uh uh Joseph you think this
is going to happen I tell you what we
are going to make sure that this
prophecy doesn't come to pass we're
going to make sure that your dream does
not come to pass so they say let's cast
him into a pit and then we will see what
becomes of his dream all right so let's
read
on verse uh what verse we just leave
over verse 20 and so let's jump down to
verse 24 they took him and cast him into
a pit and the pit was empty and there
was no water in the pit and check out
verse 25 and they sat down to do what to
eat bread and they lifted up their eyes
and looked and behold a company of
Israelites came from Gilead with their
camels bearing spicery and bomb and myrr
going to carry it down to Egypt and
Judah said to his brother what profit is
it if we slay our brother and conceal
his blood come let us sell him to the
Israelites and let not our hand be upon
him but he is our brother and our flesh
and his Brethren were
content I want you to imagine that
scenario Joseph is in his pit and he's
probably
hungry and what are they doing they're
eating bread while their brother suffers
they're eating bread while hating their
brother listen
carefully they're eating
bread whose bread was it
anyway Who provided for them yeah the
dad the father they're eating bread
while hating their
brother okay let me try it on this side
over
here they are eating
bread the father's
bread while hating their
brother all right let's see if this side
gets it now they're eating bread while
hating their brother all right so so
just just keep that in
mind and so here's what we have
happening so they sell Joseph uh into
captivity and they have now in their
minds gotten rid of Joseph why because
he's not one of us he is not one of us
so we're going to cut off our
relationship with him and we're going to
cut off his relationship with his
father and so verse 31 and they took
Joseph's coat and killed a kid of goats
uh kid of the goats and dipped The Cat
In The Blood and they sent the cat of
Many Colors and they brought it to their
father and said this we have found no no
know now whether it be thy son's Cod or
no and a new and said it is my son's cat
and evil Beast has devoured him Joseph
is without doubt rent in pieces and
Jacob rent his clothes and put sackcloth
upon his loins and mourned for his son
many days mourn for his son many days
and so out of sight out of mind they
have ritten him off let us see what will
become of
his
dream there's the story we're not
finished with the story yet
but I want to share with you that there
is an amazing parallel in this story you
see the Bible tells us our opening text
was 1 Corinthians 10 which said no uh uh
that that the things that were written
um in the past regarding Israel are
written for our admonition upon whom the
ends of the world are
come you see beloved I want to talk to
you today about
you about you
um in Romans 2: 28 we're told this he is
not a Jew which is one outwardly but he
is a Jew which is one what inwardly so
in the New Testament Israel represents
who the people of God Christians amen
and praise God for the early church yeah
and they began a work and their work was
to feed the flock you're not hearing me
the work of God's people was to feed the
flock and so God raised up the church
but you know as time went on things
start to happen within God's church and
there started to be divisions among
Brethren
so it's very interesting
that that Joseph is one of the youngest
Brothers one of the newest of Israel on
the
scene
Joseph the
father is about to send Joseph to check
on his Brethren who are supposed to be
feeding the
flock obviously because a father has
some concerns about his other
children what I have called you to do
and so Joseph the youngest of one of the
youngest of the brothers one of the New
Kids on the Block if you will is sent
to Che this out
the
brothers don't like Joseph my microphone
is not
on
Wow can you hear
me you can hear
me stay away from the
mic all right you uh you can hear me all
right do I have to start over
all
right okay so good now I don't have to
talk so
loud
so where was I I was getting excited
right the brothers listen
carefully why don't the brothers like
Joseph because he keeps the Commandments
of God
no
wait not only do they hate him because
he keeps the Commandments of God but
they also hate him because God had given
him the spirit
of oh wait a minute wait a minut pastor
are you trying to tell me that the story
of Joseph is an actuality the story
of the remnant
Church yeah that's what I'm telling
you what I'm telling you is that God has
other children not of this
flock that that he cares about and that
he's concerned about so God raised up
this movement at the end of time at the
very end of time do I need to use the
microphone all right just uh shut this
off
okay so God brought this movement at the
end of
time to
check come
on Joseph
Joseph
Joseph I need you to go check on your
brethren
and so Joseph comes upon the scene but
when he comes upon the scene we
understand that the brother's reaction
to him is one of hatred is one of anger
why because oh he keeps the Commandments
of
God they're probably thinking he thinks
he's better than
us oh and what you have a
prophecy that that at the end of time we
are going to come to
you are are you guys are you with
me and so they're like yeah yeah yeah
we're going to like put it like this day
if I if we were back in in those days uh
the brothers of Joseph if they had
internet they would have gone online and
started saying all kinds of bad things
about Joseph Joseph yeah let me tell you
what happened to Joseph when he was 8
years
old and let me tell you something else
about Joseph and they would have derided
Joseph and they would have set up all
these all manner of evil things about
Joseph they would have brought an evil
report against
Joseph
interesting interesting because beloved
as we look at the history of what God
did in this movement as we look at the
parallels between the story of Joseph
and the story of God's end time Movement
we see an amazing parallel because the
Bible says the dragon was angry and me
went to make war with those that keep
the Commandments of God and have the
testimony of Jesus and we're told in
Revelation chap 19:10 that the testimony
of Jesus is the spirit of Prophecy and
beloved listen to me the spirit of
Prophecy does not mean that one
individual was given the gift of
understanding the future it means listen
carefully that God has given this church
a special understanding of end time
events praise God for what he has given
us through the writings through the uh
uh the writings of of of the that we
call the spirit of Prophecy but remember
this that the spirit of Prophecy was
given to the entire church meaning God
has given us understanding of what is to
come in the
future
so the brothers
say we're going to call you a cult I
mean we're going to throw you in a
pit we're going to make sure that that
you the world knows you don't really
have a connection with the
father we're going to make sure that you
are not counted as one of us no you go
someplace else because we don't like you
out of sight out of
mind and you can
imagine that have as Joseph is sold into
captivity you can imagine that perhaps
Joseph in his own mind is thinking the
prophecies how are they going to come to
pass
now imagine Joseph probably wondering
probably being tempted imagine the
brother saying yep prophecies will never
come to pass
now by the way Joseph this prophecy that
you said is so outlandish
it is so off the wall us bow down to you
it is so off the wall it will never
happen Sunday
law you're
serious you guys actually believe that
that in this country in the United
States of America
that there is going to be something
called a Sunday law are you serious
don't make me
laugh and you actually believe that that
that that there's going to be something
called a image that is set up and you
actually believe that that people from
from all these churches are wrong but
you're
right you think you're better than
everybody you think you're the father's
favorite
and so Joseph is
sold
and as he sold into
captivity various things begin to happen
to Joseph you know the
story in the next chapter he is being
tempted by a
woman and um what does Joseph do
does he fall or does he
overcome he overcome listen Joseph at
this point is going through a time of
trial and it's as though God is allowing
these things to happen to him and you
must in as you read the story you must
wonder God why would you allow Joseph to
go through these things he's being sold
into captivity he's tempted he's I mean
he ends up in prison
as if being sold into slavery wasn't bad
enough he ends up in prison and so all
these things are happening to Joseph but
we can say one thing about Joseph praise
God Joseph
overcame Joseph overcame so I want you
to focus on two things that Joseph does
while he is away from his brothers
number one Joseph what overcame number
two you remember the story where Joseph
is in prison and he uh there's a dream
the there are two people the Butler and
the baker they have a dream and in the
dream uh they see these three days and
then Joseph interprets the dream one of
you are going to be saved the other
one's going to be lost yes now after
this
happens uh Joseph says to the guy that's
save hey remember me right remember me
and the guy gets out does he remember
Joseph no he doesn't it is not until
like a long time later that Pharaoh has
a
dream and in the dream Pharaoh sees
something very
disturbing he doesn't know what he's
looking at yet but it's a famine that's
coming you guys remember that and so
he's trying to find out what the dream
means no one can interpret the dream and
then the guy that Joseph spoke to in
prison says oh yeah I remember this guy
in prison his name is Joseph and so God
I mean so Pharaoh calls Joseph and and
then Joseph tells Pharaoh listen this is
what's going to happen and I want you to
notice with me go with me to Genesis
41 Genesis 41 and I want you to notice
with me Genesis 41
verse we'll start with
verse
25 and Joseph said unto Pharaoh the
dream is one of pharaoh is one God has
showed Pharaoh what he's about to do the
seven good kind are seven years and the
Seven good ears are seven years the
dream is one and the Seven thin and ill-
favored kind that come up after the
seven come of them are seven years and
the Seven empty years blasted with the
East uh blasted with the East Wind shall
be seven years of famine this is the
thing which I have spoken unto Pharaoh
what God is about to do he showeth unto
Pharaoh so he's telling him hey there's
going to be seven years of plenty
followed by seven years of
famine now listen carefully guys because
there's something here that you need to
see in verse 33 now Jo now therefore let
Pharaoh look out a man discreet and wise
and set him over the land of Egypt let
Pharaoh do this and let him appoint
officers over the land and take up the
fifth part of the land of Egypt uh of
the land of Egypt in the seven plenteous
years and let them gather all the food
of those good years that come and lay up
corn under the hand of of pharaoh and
let them keep food in the cities and the
food that shall be for store to the land
against the seven years of famine which
shall be in the land of Egypt that that
the land perish not through the famine
and so God says I'm sorry Pharaoh says
Joseph I appoint you to do that work so
what is Joseph now
doing he is gathering
bread he is gathering bread
two
things while his brothers are out there
doing their thing God is preparing
Joseph for something amazing and the way
that he prepares him is twofold one by
helping him overcome two by gathering
bread I I don't know if you you you feel
this but God is preparing Joseph for
something very important number
one he's going to see can Joseph
overcome and number
two he's going to let Joseph gather
bread now I got a question for you why
is Joseph Gathering
bread because because what because a
famine is
coming a famine is
coming and and what God does is he set
sets Joseph apart listen carefully to
save the very
ones and the way he does this he says
Joseph I need you to learn how to
overcome and Joseph I need you to gather
bread because the time is
coming where there's going to be a
famine in the
land not a famine of bread nor a thirst
of water but of hearing the word of the
Lord a time is coming
Joseph if your name is Joseph raise your
hand some of you didn't get that so
we're going to try it again if your name
is Joseph raise your hand okay good you
got it there's more than one
Joseph yeah there's more than one Jo
there's more than two Joseph in
here so Joseph a time is coming where
your brothers are going to come looking
for
bread and Joseph if you are not
Gathering bread
now if you are not in the time of Plenty
learning what it means to gather bread
you see Joseph I didn't call you into
Egypt I didn't call you because I wanted
you to gather bread for yourself and
feed
yourself Joseph you have a
responsibility to gather bread why not
so that you can save yourself
Joseph you see Joseph if you enter into
this thing with an attitude of I gather
bread for myself so I can choose when I
want to eat and when I don't want to eat
then you're you've entered into this
thing with a selfish attitude Joseph you
got to understand that I'm saving you
not for
you I'm calling you not just for you
Joseph I'm calling you because I have
some sheep of other
flock who I love Joseph as much as I
love you no they got it wrong you're not
my favorite I love all of
you but Joseph since you are willing to
obey me since you are willing to keep
the Commandments of God I've given you
the spirit of
Prophecy and I've given you the spirit
of Prophecy Joseph not so that you can
be exalted and oh look at Joseph and how
could it no Joseph because a time is
coming where your brothers are going to
need
you Joseph are you preparing for that
moment or are you living
selfishly are you preparing for that
moment knowing that you are your
brother's
keeper you see beloved if I get up every
day and I don't think if I'm not
thinking you know what man I need to arm
myself with the word of God today why
because there's someone out there who is
hungry who is in a famine and I have to
feed the
hungry then then I will get up every day
like this oh the word of God well you
know what I already know the truth why
should I study today I've already got
truth and you become you start to live a
self centered
Christianity but God says no Joseph I
called you because there are others out
there who I love and I'm using you to
reach those those others it would have
been absolutely irresponsible for Joseph
in Egypt not to gather bread knowing
what was
coming how responsible is it of of
us to know that something is
coming and yet not
prepare for that coming
famine you see beloved listen the Bible
says in Matthew 4:4 man shall not live
by bread alone but by every what word
that proceeds out of the mouth of God so
God tells us I want you to gather bread
give us this day our daily bread I want
you to think about this God has daily
bread for you
God has daily bread for you so think
about this every day you can be
gathering bread by the way do you know
this happened in the Old Testament do
you know God rain down Mana from Heaven
every
day except for
one the Sabbath now
now
listen God Reed Mana down he reigned it
down on the first day of the week
and what did you have to
do you had to get it
when that day that day you couldn't get
yesterday's
bread today no no no no no if you wanted
yesterday's bread you would have had to
be present to get the
bread beloved listen to me do you know
do you know listen you ready for a
shock last
Monday God had a special piece of bread
for
you how many of you got that piece of
bread on Monday don't raise your hand
don't raise your hand don't raise your
hand I'm just asking the question last
Monday God last Tuesday God said and on
today's
menu
amen but if you were not present on
Tuesday to get the bread guess what you
missed the bread
do do you catch
that every day so so God rained on bread
on on the first day of the week on the
second day on the third and then on the
sixth day guess what he rang down a
double
portion you want to know why because he
was not going to rain any bread down on
Sabbath so please think about
this many of us come to church on
Sabbath looking for
bread and what happens is uh we we
reverse the equation because God was
reigning bread down throughout the week
but then none on
Sabbath see when when you came to
Sabbath you were already coming with
bread you were already
filled but but most of us the way we do
it is we flip the equation so no bread
on Sunday no bread on Monday no bread on
Tuesday no bread on Wednesday no bread
on Thursday no bread on Friday and then
on Sabbath we expect to be
fed but what happens is you know the
sermon comes and and appeals are made
and and the bread just really doesn't
have that much of an
effect so so what's happening is you
know appeal after appeal and all right
how many of us are going to do this how
many are going to do that and you know
it easy for us to raise your oh yeah
mm but the reason we can't follow up on
those commitments is because we haven't
been being fed throughout the week and
remember God doesn't reain Bread on
Sabbath He reigns it all through the
week when you come into Sabbath you
should be coming in filled with the
glory of the
Lord so so God says Joseph I need you to
gather bread why because a time of
famine is coming and Joseph I need you
to understand that this bread is not
about me saving you I know what I've
done for you yes I've raised you up to
be the second in command in all of Egypt
but that's not why I'm telling you to
gather bread Joseph I'm not patting you
on the back Joseph a time is coming
where I'm going to need you because I'm
saving others Joseph gather bread do you
know what God is telling you to do right
now he's telling you to gather
bread he's telling you I want you to get
into the word of God why not just for
yourself but because I need to use you
like I use Joseph to reach his brothers
who are of other foes at the end of time
it is your respons it would be
irresponsible for you as Joseph as the
Seventh Day Adventist Church to sit here
day after day after day and not be
gathering bread knowing that the
salvation of others is on the
line gather bread okay just in case
you're mad at me want you to say these
words we love you Pastor
Myers come on no you didn't smile we
love you Pastor
Myers and only half of you said it and I
know at the end the sermon most you
going to walk out that door right there
I'm not shaking his hand
beloved
listen God Was preparing Joseph to
save his
enemies God Was preparing Joseph to save
those who could eat while hating him
God Was preparing Joseph to to save
those who would not feed him to to to
deliver those who are ready to kill
him do you realize what kind of spirit
you must have in order to do
that you must be like
Jesus you see Beloved the bread is not
just a representation of the word of God
the bread is a repres representation of
Jesus himself Jesus says I am the bread
of life it's as though the father was
saying come on Joseph I need you you and
I together I'm going to work through you
to save those who hate
us
us Joseph they hate you because they
hate
me they reject you because they reject
me so Joseph you and I no God doesn't
say Joseph I'm taking you and um let
them go to
hell did you understand what I just said
right don't think let them be
lost he's not saying that he's saying
Joseph come on you and I are going to
save those who are on their way to
hell you and I are going to work
together to save those who hate us who
despise us can you imagine the love of
God because if if if if it were some of
us we would take all right come on you
and the rest of you you're
lost but God said no I love them too
much Joseph and I need you to love them
the same way so Joseph I need to make
you like
Jesus so you know what I'm going to
do I'm going to allow you to be hated by
your
brethren I'm going to allow you to be
sold for
silver I am Jo Joseph going to allow
you to
descend into a
pit to descend into I'm going to give
I'm going to walk you through the
process of going lower and lower and
lower so that you can finally be exalted
to the right hand of the highest in
authority and Joseph while you're going
through your trial I'm going to have you
between two men a butler and a baker and
at the end of three days one of them
will be lost and one will be
saved Joseph I'm going to allow you to
walk through the experience of Jesus I'm
going to send you to a place so that you
can prepare a place for your
brothers what Jesus what God is doing is
he is preparing Joseph by making him not
only a receiver of the word but also a
receiver of Jesus Christ because listen
carefully Joseph may have been Gathering
the bread but if he didn't have the
heart of Jesus what would have happened
when the brothers came was this hm I
remember that you guys wouldn't feed me
so I am not going to feed
you no no no no
no you know what Joseph does when his
brothers come to him
they don't even know it Joseph walks out
the room and he
weeps beloved how do you feel about
those who hate you and despitefully use
you how do you feel you know how do you
feel about people who talk about your
church God I can't wait to you know some
of us would go out and if if they were
getting saved we' go out and weep why
Lord why are you saving
them Joseph wasn't weeping like that J
Joseph wept because he wanted his
brothers redeemed and when he saw that
their actions listen care look his
brothers came to him in time of
famine the very thing that they swore up
and down would never happen the very
thing they were certain of ha what what
prophecy it'll never happen that very
thing God orchestrated events so if some
of you are struggling right now say I
don't see how a Sunday law is going to
be passed
how can it look at things imagine Joseph
in Egypt how in the world would God
bring to pass the prophecy he gave
Joseph saying your brothers will bow
down before
you belov we have a prophecy it says
many people are going to come out of
Babylon and and check this out remember
in Joseph's dream it said the brothers
brought their
sheaves what is a sheave
yeah you know what the gospel commission
is it is to go out and bring in the she
bringing in the she bringing in the she
don't ask me to sing don't anyone come
to me Pastor why don't you try join the
choir it's not going to happen bringing
in the
sheaves the prophecy stated that the
brothers would bring their she to Joseph
amen I know the brothers are looking at
you right now you know what you're the
youngest of us man you just got on the
scene in 1844 we've been
here we've been here man and you're
going to come on a scene and think you
know better than us and think that
you're God's favorite and think that but
no beloved it's not like that we're
we're not we're God doesn't look at us
and say yeah you're my favorite he says
look you're the one I'm going to use to
redeem your brothers because they are my
favorites because I love
them and this is not just those who
don't keep the Commandments in other
churches these are those who don't keep
the Commandments whether they're
atheists or whatever else God says I
don't care who they are I've called you
Joseph to gather bread because the time
is coming where the hungry are going to
be seeking the word of
God and if you're not ready how are you
going to feed the hungry
so I was uh um studying with these
Hebrew Israelites two days ago they said
let's meet in Barnes and Nobles I think
I've told you about them before these uh
they're they're they're um
African-American and they believe that
the true Hebrews are
africanamerican and that you know uh
anyone else or or that listen carefully
that that white people specifically are
not the people of God and are going to
be slaves to black people in the
future and they take the Bible and they
show all these verses you know talking
about you know the Israelites being in
captivity and see black people were in
captivity and so here I am dialoguing
with them and I've been talking with
them for months now sharing with them
the the the Three Angels messages you
know we're going back and forth and I'm
like Lord you know I don't know cuz it
just you know I I stump these guys all
the time that I would have to go back
and check that out and then they come
back with some just you in my estimation
just off the wall so we're sitting there
in Barnes & Noble talking and and and
discussing this thing and and we're
sitting there for about an hour and a
half when suddenly I and they you know
they they like to talk loud you know so
brother read read uh Exodus 25 and the
brother read ex 25 says and I'm in the
library like you know Baron no like man
just just hold it down man you I don't
want people like and all of a sudden I
hear this voice behind me de you mind if
I interrupt and I turn turned around and
it was a white guy and I was like
oh and I'm thinking to my I look back at
them and I'm like please I'm just
thinking man please do not do just
please I'm thinking I'm praying and the
guy's like um you know I couldn't help
but overhear your
conversation and uh you know we were on
on a on a particular verse actually was
Galatians 3:27 and he starts to answer
the question he's a Christian he's like
you know I just overheard your
conversation it was just so you know I
just couldn't resist and we get into
this dialogue and now he's there with us
and I'm just trying to think myself man
he doesn't even know what they believe
cuz he didn't know what they
believe and I'm thinking okay how am I
going to like you know maneuver this
between him cuz I'm looking at him now
like okay and so as he's talking I start
writing down my number I'm like and I
slip on my I said hey here's my number
give me yours he's still talking he's
like no problem so he gives me his
number and then we we are we talk for
like another half hour so then I have to
leave I leave and he and the Hebrew
Israelites spent like another I don't
know half an hour
talking so I get home and around 9:30 at
night I get this text hey this is Tobias
that you met in the uh Barnes and&
Nobles today 9:30 I called them up we
talked for like an hour and a
half and after we talked and we shared
you know yeah that it just seems like
they're confused about this and that you
know what I did cuz my eye was already
on I was like hey have you have you ever
heard of the sanctuary oh no a little
bit anyway so I have a study with him
next
Thursday guys listen I didn't have a
shirt on my chest saying I am a
pastor that could have been any one of
you sitting in that Barns and Nobles
that could have made that kind of
connection and what I'm trying to say to
you is listen I am not afraid because
you know what I do my hobby is gathering
bread now you might think that's your
hobby because you're paid for it no
please don't think that don't think it's
the pastor's responsibility to gather
bread and then feed us no my name is
Joseph and your name is
Joseph it it that that doesn't matter
God is not like well you're not paid to
do this so it's all right you don't have
to do it leave it to the professional no
there are no professional knows God has
called every one of us because there is
someone that you can reach that nobody
else can
reach so beloved my appeal to you as we
close I'm going to call ask Marco to
come forward he's going to pray for us
as we close my appeal to you is very
simple two things Lord teach me to
overcome and help me to gather
bread help me to
realize that it is not so that I can
save myself but you have called me
because you have sheep of other
foes them you must bring
to I want to invite you to
kneel as Marco leads us in
prayer Heavenly Father thank you for
your Sabbath day thank you for this
message help us to be like Joseph that
he stood
firm in your word in your
promises help us to share the bread of
life to those around
us help us next week bringing new people
to you because we know that a lot of
people have the need to know you
help
us as a whole
church to be United to have the spirit
of sharing the good and the wonderful
Words of
Life as we
close our worship
service I want to ask you for a special
blessing for those visitors that will be
coming for those sharing your
word Lord help us to
find the special person that you need
for your
glory Lord we know that you're coming
very
soon and we
have the commitment with you to share
your word with others
now that we are going to be having lunch
bless all the hands that have provided
the
food take us home and help us to be
safe in your precious
name amen